Guide to Ralph Anderson, Jr. papers, 1860-1989 MS 413
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series VII: Professional Affiliation, 1946-1989
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Memberships
    - American Institute of Architects, News Clippings, 1948-1972 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - American Institute of Architects, Memorabilia, 1949-1966 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - American Institute of Architects, Election of Ralph Anderson, President of Houston Chapter, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - American Institute of Architects, Lectures (Ralph Anderson), 1965 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - American Institute of Architects, Miscellaneous Lectures, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - American Institute of Architects, Ralph Anderson Nomination for Fellowship, 1965-67 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - American Institute of Architects, Correspondence, 1965-1989 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Texas Architects Committee, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Series VIII: Personal, 1937-1989
  Personal interests of Ralph Anderson, Jr. away from the architectural drawing board can be found in the Personal series. He had an extremely wide diversity of interests that ranged from cultural, literary to civic.
  Included in the series are the draft and final copy of Handcar White, Battle History of the 2nd BN. 328th Infantry Regiment, WWII and other miscellaneous writings of Ralph Anderson, Jr. Correspondence relating to his association with Billboard Limited, the Shepherd Society and the Texas Educational Foundation can be found in his series. There is also an extensive collection of theatrical programs, ticket stubs, brochures and other miscellaneous items from his many trips. Material is filed chronologically by the year of each trip. Of particular interest is the diary that Ralph Anderson kept through the last year of his life.
  - Subseries A:Literary Writings and Correspondence
    - Lamar High School, Class Correspondent, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Book Reviews by Ralph Anderson, 1940-1941 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Draft of Handcar White, Ralph Anderson, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Handcar White by Ralph Anderson, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Mis. Writings by Ralph Anderson, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Mis. Writings by Ralph Anderson (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1950 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Writings by David Cohn, Aldous Huxley, Ernest Krenek, n. d. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B: Memberships and Affiliations
    - National Geographic Society, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Membership Allegro, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Billboards, Limited (see Publications), 1985-1989 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Houston Ballet, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - University of Texas College of Education Advisory Council, 1988-1989 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Shepherd Society, 1988-1989 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Tejas Club, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: General Memorabilia
    - School Patches and Ribbons, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Lamar High School, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Ticket Stubs, Christmas Cards, 1939-1946 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Theater and Musical Programs, 1939-1947 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Invitations, 1939-1954 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Invitations, n. d. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939-1989 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Financial, 1943-1965 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Insurance, 1984-1988 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Retirement Party, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Diary, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Lamar High School Reunion, Class of 1939, n. d. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1942-1949 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Wresting Program, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - U. S. Senate Pass, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Passport, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Child's Pants (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Hunting and Fishing Guide, Texas Coast (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Subseries D: Ralph Anderson Residence (Box 18, Folder 7-10)
    - Correspondence, Ralph Anderson Townhouse, 1960-1962 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Publicity, Ralph Anderson Townhouse, 1961-1964 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Requests for House plans, Ralph Anderson Townhouse, 1963-1967 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Remodeling, Ralph Anderson Townhouse, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Subseries E: Trips, Playbills, Ticket Stubs, Theatrical Programs, Miscellaneous
    - Playbills: Boston, New York, 1939-1944 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Playbills: Boston, Houston, New York, 1948-1951 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Trips: California, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Trips: Chicago, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Trips: South America, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Trips: Europe, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Trips: Holland, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Trips: Europe, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Map and Guidebook/Mexico and El Salvador, 1947-1948 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Series IX: Publications, 1948-1989
  The publications series has an interesting collection of newspaper clippings that give an excellent overall view of Ralph Anderson's social life and civic endeavors. He was interested not only in architectural aesthetics, but he was also interested in environmental aesthetics as shown by his involvement and commitment to "Billboards Limited."
  - Subseries A: Newspaper Clippings, Brochures
    - Newspaper Column by Ralph Anderson, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Glenn McCarthy, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Ralph Anderson (Social), 1961-1971 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Harris County Dome Stadium, 1965-1971 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Regulation of Billboards (see Personal), 1965-1977 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968, n. d. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Rice University, Friends of Fondren, 1975, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Lamar High Class of 1939 Reunion, 1979, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Andy Anderson (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Rice Hotel, n. d. (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Houston Medical Center, n. d. (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Series X: General Photographs, 1927-1977
  The photographic series consist of pictures of Ralph Anderson taken through many phases of his life, from babyhood to adulthood.
  There are also pictures of Ralph Anderson, Sr. with President Dwight Eisenhower in 1953 and one taken with General Douglas McArthur.
  - Subseries A: Ralph and Andy Anderson, Friends
    - Ralph Anderson as Baby (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Ralph Anderson as Baby (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Ralph Anderson as Baby (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Ralph Anderson as Baby (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Ralph Anderson as Young Boy, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Ralph Anderson as Young Boy (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Ralph Anderson as Young Boy (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Ralph Anderson as Young Boy (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Ralph Anderson, South America, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Ralph Anderson, England, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Ralph Anderson as Grown Man, 1950-1977 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Ralph Anderson as Professional, 1965-1970 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Ralph Anderson Later Years (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Ralph Anderson's Home (and slides) (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Brinkman and Boehm Wedding (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Andy Anderson and President Dwight Eisenhower, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Andy Anderson and General Douglas McArthur (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 1946-51 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified, n. d. (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Post Cards, n. d. (Box 21, Folder 20)
- Series XI: Oversize, 1900-1969
  This series contains a photograph album with pictures of the inside and the outside of the home of Ralph Anderson, Jr., a picture of the Company B, A.S.T.U., United States Army dated 1943 and a picture of the Rhea Building, Houston, 1900.
  There are newspapers with headlines relating to World War II. There is also a JFK Memorial Edition of Life Magazine, along with some miscellaneous brochures.
  - Subseries A: Newspapers, Brochures, Magazines, Photographs
    - Rockefeller Center Brochure, 1938 (Box 22)
    - Fondren Library Brochure, 1946 (Box 22)
    - Houston Post, 1941-1969 (Box 22)
    - Stars and Stripes, 1945 (Box 22)
    - Grapevine, 26 Infantry Division, 1945 (Box 22)
    - Mexico City Herald, 1948 (Box 22)
    - Market Square Gazette, 1967 (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous Newspapers, 1943-1948 (Box 22)
    - Life Magazine, 1963 (Box 22)
    - Photograph, Rhea Building, 1900 (Box 22)
    - Photograph, Company B WWII, 1943 (Box 22)
    - Photograph, Ralph Anderson Home (Box 22)